[offscreen] You know...
Do you want everything to stand out?
Post-traumatic stress.
It's not a personal failing,
but rather a treatable malfunction
with certain biological mechanisms
that allow us to cope
with dangerous experiences.
But what if you don't
want to manage your way through life,
exposing yourself to a painful past
in a safe and supportive environment can
be a way of dealing with trauma head-on
so that you can stop avoiding life
and start living it freely.
That's for you're new book?
Published once a draft in three weeks.
You'll get it done.
You always get it done.
What do you think?
It's red.
It's not red.
It's wrath.
It took me two dozen
combinations to get this exact hue.
[car honking ahead]
Yeah, that's what happens.
Can't fight rush hour.
We wouldn't be stuck in rush
hour of the movers that come on time.
They do it on purpose.
Make excuses about running late.
Knowing if they work past five,
we get charged an extra day.
Not everyone is as manipulative
as you think, sweetheart.
And not everyone is as guileless.
Miyamoto.
Especially when they get paid by the hour.
Well, they're on their way now.
And this time tomorrow
we'll be in our beautiful new house,
unpacking our beautiful things.
I can't believe we're doing this.
I've never not lived in the city.
Oh, you'll love it.
Trees, mountains, ...
Deer.
Ticks. Mosquitoes.
Rednecks.
Is there even Wi-Fi?
Maybe spotty in some places, but
where there's no Wi-Fi,
there's better connection.
[Will] Hey, Sam, you want to try driving?
[Sam] Really?
[Evelyn] I don't think so.
[Will] So there's barely
any cars out here.
It's a perfect place to get our feet wet.
[Evelyn] We've discussed this.
[Sam] I haven't had a
seizure in over a year.
[Evelyn] We'll talk about it once
you're back on your medication.
[Will] Okay, listen, how about this?
Once we're settled into our new place
and Sam's back on our medication.
We'll go out.
I'll teach you how
to drive. Okay? It's okay.
[Sam] Whatever.
You need some help?
I can't quite figure
out how to make this...
They make these things
unnecessarily complicated.
I've never done this before.
Don't be too hard on yourself.
I mean, my years ago
pop up tents with the way to go
in my humble opinion.
I'm Steve.
Wife and kids are over there.
My wife Evelyn is inside, and
our daughter Samantha's around somewhere.
She's here for the weekend.
Oh, no. No, just the night.
We, actually bought a
house down in Emporium.
Thought we'd make a little
camping trip out of the move.
Emporium's a nice town.
We're up in Ridgeway,
just a hop, skip away.
Hey, we're cooking s'mores later.
If you'd like to join.
This might take you up on that.
Come by any time.
[Evelyn] Who was that?
Steve.
Would you like to make a s'more?
I'm good.
Can I tell a ghost story?
Here we go.
Little ritual of ours.
Go ahead, son.
There once was an old woman
who went into the woods.
Dig up some roots for dinner.
When suddenly she came
across something ugly toad!
Oh, God. Not this one again.
Mary swore.
Mary.
He tells this story every time.
[Noah] Do not!
I think it's a great story.
Go ahead Noah.
Those two are always at each other.
Not that I blame her.
He does tell this story every
single time we go camping.
He's obsessed.
You camp a lot?
Only, like ...
200 times a year.
My dad has a thing for the great outdoors.
Thinks it brings us closer to God.
story being told in background
What about you?
You guys do a lot of camping?
First time.
Really?
What do you think?
It's ... okay.
It's pretty lame sometimes.
Like now.
Never find a better view.
I'm Luke.
Sam.
I eat your hairy toad!
The woman shouted.
Yes you did, the giant said.
Nobody ever saw the old woman again.
The only clue to her
disappearance was a big footprint
next to her house with a missing big toe.
The end.
[clapping]
Hey, do you guys want
to hear a real ghost story?
There was a girl in the
1800s who lived in this area.
Her family was super conservative
and wouldn't let her go out with boys.
But little did they know,
she'd fallen in love with a guy.
And the two of them
would sneak off into the woods
every day to kiss under
the covers of trees.
Gross!
It wasn't long before she got pregnant.
And knowing her father would be mad,
she asked her boyfriend for help.
Only to learn that he wanted
nothing to do with her.
Seeing no other choice,
she went home and as expected,
her father was furious.
He threw her out
and told her to never come back.
So she ended up on the streets
begging for food and shelter.
But no one would help her.
Nine months later, she gave birth.
Starving and cold,
she took her baby to a nearby bridge.
What story is this?
The girl looked down into the black water
and saw the answers to her problems.
She and the baby would leave
this miserable world together.
It's said that if you go to that bridge,
you could still hear the baby's cries.
And if you're pregnant,
the vengeful ghost will kill you.
And you're...
[Steve] Okay.
That's enough.
You let him tell a stupid story!
Where did you hear this? From my app.
What app?
Some folklore app.
You put in your location and it
tells you all the legends in the area.
This one happened right up the road.
Take it off your phone.
It's just a story.
Mary!
Obey thy father.
Hear those?
Hey. You okay?
Samantha?
Hey, kiddo, it's dad, can you hear me?
This happens sometimes.
It's been a long day.
I think we're going to turn in.
There we go.
Good job. Okay, there we are.
Okay.
You guys okay?
Thanks for the s'mores.
[Door shuts]
Morning!
How long was I out?
Not long.
Well, now they
definitely think I'm a freak.
No one thinks you're a freak.
That's why I don't want
you driving, though.
Yeah. Got it.
Where's dad?
On the phone with his publisher.
You can't rush these things, Kathleen.
I'm really happy.
I think it's the best work of my career.
We're going to leave as soon as he's done.
There's something resembling
showers up the path.
You wanna wash up?
I see you figured out how to roll her up.
Took a few tries,
but I think I've got it down.
How's Samantha?
Oh. Much better. Thanks.
I was wondering which way
you plan on taking to Emporium?
Uhh..
I think it's route 20.
20 will take you forever.
Highway's faster. Safer too.
[Evelyn] Safer?
Never know where you're going
to get on the back roads.
Fallen trees, flooded creek beds.
Potholes the size of a Buick.
Plus, there's not a lick cell service
once you hit Clinton.
Of course not.
If you take a left out of here,
you can be on the highway in 15 minutes.
Thanks, but I think we're
going to take the scenic route.
Are you a God-fearing man, Will?
Can't say that I am, Steve.
Whatever you believe,
you can't deny the fact there are things
in this world that mean to do you harm.
when you realize it
or not, evil does exist.
That bridge my daughter brought
up last night is an example of it.
You have to cross that
bridge if you take 20, Will.
I saw the state of your daughter.
You know what, Steve?
As much as I respect your views,
I don't really believe in
vengeful spirits.
Maybe it's time you should.
You sure you know where you're going?
That thing doesn't seem to think so.
We've become too dependent on technology.
Give me an old fashioned map any day.
Will!
I memorized the directions
before we left, okay?
Might not be the fastest way, but
it'll be the most visually pleasing.
What's "deer processing?"
[Will] You don't want to know.
Why are we stopping?
Just taking in the beautiful view.
Is that the bridge that
girl was talking about?
I don't know, let's check it out. Sam?
I feel like I'm gonna get tetanus
just by looking at this thing.
Will you two get over here?
The view is unbelievable!
You know, there's probably rats, Will.
We don't have rats in
the country, sweetheart.
They're called squirrels.
Sam? Come on.
A lot of work went
into building this bridge.
Especially back in those days.
[Will] Any thoughts?
What?
Looks like you got something on your mind.
Just taking the beautiful view.
What?
[Evelyn] This is even safe to drive over?
We'll make a woods woman of her yet.
Sam?
I'll be right there.
[Evelyn] Ahhh!
I think these things
are actually attracting them to me.
Litter much?
It's biodegradable.
Right...
I'm going back to the car.
Oh. I've had enough beauty for one day.
Stay on the trail.
Can I see?
Oh, wow.
That's pretty great.
[Sam] It's just a cloth.
So, how are you doing?
Fine.
Can I get another adjective, please?
I'm...
Great. Dad.
You can actually hear yourself think.
Yeah.
So you want to tell me
what you're thinking about?
Nothing.
I know that's not true, you're too smart.
I don't know, just ... stuff.
What happened at that
school wasn't your fault.
You know that.
You're not a bad person or any
of the other dumb things those kids...
I seriously don't care what
they have to say about me.
Look.
I really don't feel like having
a therapy session right now.
I'm not trying to be your therapist
I'm just trying to be your dad.
Is what you were thinking about have
anything to do with your being adopted?
Because if it does, that's okay.
I know we've talked about this before,
but it's actually pretty common
for adopted people, to
to be curious ...
They feel disconnected...
Not knowing where you came from or
the circumstances around your adoption.
That can be confusing.
There's nothing wrong with you Sam.
And I'm going to do everything in my power
to help you feel better.
[Will] I spy with my little
eye something green.
This whole place is green.
Makes it kind of interesting.
Leaves?
No, but. Good guess.
Evy?
Oh, come on.
Grass.
Guess again.
Fern?
The same thing as grass.
No it's not.
You're both being too obvious think,
micro not macro.
What does that even mean?
Inspection sticker.
And we have a winner.
Ding ding ding ding ding.
[Loud sound from the road]
Oh. Oh!
Everybody okay?
I think we blew a tire.
What'd you hit?
Nothing.
Okay.
I'll try AAA.
No, service, remember?
Right.
Gin.
I hate this game.
Because you always lose.
What time is it?
I know what we can do.
Sit for me.
You can try on my new makeup line.
I'm good.
Might cheer you up a little?
You're right. Mom.
Makeup solves everything.
Why is it that everything I say
or do has to turn into a fight with you?
It is not my fault that
you are in this position.
Don't forget why we're on this
little adventure in the first place.
[Evelyn] I didn't mean that.
[Sam] Yes you did.
I'm the one stupid enough to get pregnant.
I never called you stupid.
I just don't understand
why you want to go through with this.
You have your whole
life ahead of you, Samantha.
We sent you to the best schools.
We gave you the best of everything.
You have all our connections.
And for what?
You're going to be a mother at 16.
I don't even know how this happened.
Where did I go wrong?
I'm just something you did wrong?
You might want to add some
lipstick. Looking a little thin.
Where are you going, Samantha!?
Ugh!
[sounds of a baby crying]
Oh my God!
[baby crying continues]
[Sam coughing]
You okay?
Yeah.
It's not every day
you see someone from drowning.
What were you doing out there?
I thought I heard something.
Where are your parents.
Up the road?
We got a flat tire.
My dad's trying to find
reception so we can get out.
I should go.
No, wait.
You shouldn't be out here by yourself.
Let me drive you back.
Put on your seat belt.
I'm John.
Samantha.
It's a little side business of mine.
Sam!
[Evelyn] Where were you?
Why's your hair wet?
I'm fine.
You're not fine.
She had a little accident up the road.
She's all right.
Thanks for bringing her back.
I heard you got a flat tire.
Were you able to reach anybody?
Oh, no. There's no
service out here anywhere.
Anything I can do to help?
I mean.
Can you take a look.
Sure. All right.
Thanks.
What were you thinking?
Getting into some strange man's car?
He could have taken you
to his house. Or worse.
You got to be smarter than that.
Where were you?
The bridge we crossed.
We cross that bridge hours ago.
There's no way you
could have walked that far.
What I said earlier.
Can we just drop it,
please?
That should do it.
Leave that. I got it.
What do I owe you?
I don't want your money.
I could use some water, though.
Of course.
Be right back,
Did he change the tire?
Yeah.
He wants some water.
Sorry to barge in on you.
It's starting to drizzle outside.
Thanks.
What brings you from Philly?
How did you know we were from Philly?
Must be your accent.
I didn't know we had one.
We're moving.
Moving? To which town?
Umm...
Emporium.
Never been
Nice place?
Very nice.
Has one of the best
school districts in the area.
That's great.
I'm sorry I didn't catch your name.
John.
Will.
John, I don't mean to be rude, but I
think it's time for us to be pushing off.
I understand.
Thanks for the water.
Stay safe.
[door closes]
Do me a favor.
Don't talk to strangers.
What's he doing?
Can we go now, please?
If we drive straight, we should
be at the town in about an hour.
Is that man, John Belivet?
How did you hear the name?
The article in your briefcase.
What article?
Why were you in my briefcase?
Sam. There's personal documents in there.
Patient photos? You know
better than to go through my things.
I didn't look at your patients folders.
Was it?
I believe it was.
But someone please tell me
what's going on.
I did some research on the area
and found information about a tragedy
that happened years ago.
Apparently, a man named John Belivet
threw his wife and newborn off a bridge.
The man in our camper?
I didn't realize it was him
until he was inside.
Oh, that's great.
Our pregnant daughter
driving around with a man
who likes to kill women and children.
Why isn't he in jail?
I guess he finished his sentence.
Why are you researching him?
Good question.
I research lots of things.
Grocery stores, lawn care services.
Homicidal maniacs.
But why keep the article?
What's so important about it, though?
It's late. Now's not
the time to get into it.
Get in to what?
We'll talk about it tomorrow.
I want to talk about it now.
Will?
what's going on?
Is he My dad?
What are you talking about?
Will, what is she talking about?
Is he?
I was going to tell you
when the time was right.
[Evelyn] What?
What time was that?
You told me the agency didn't
tell you about my biological parents.
They didn't.
I called the agency
a couple of months back
when everything was happening at the school.
You did what?
I thought knowing your background
might give me more tools.
As we work through
your emotional challenges.
The bridge you took us to.
Is that where it happened?
I was hoping that if I exposed you
to the location, eventually
we could confront your past trauma,
which might be unconsciously
influencing your current feel.
Cut the psychobabble
Will, for Christ's sake.
So now I'm just some
experiment, for your book.
Has nothing to do with the book, sweetie.
This is all about helping you.
This is so messed up.
Sam.
[car swerves]
Did you fall asleep? No.
Where are we?
Almost there.
You said we'd be there in an hour.
It's late. Just pull over.
I'll go pop the camper.
I gotta pee.
You go first.
I'll shine the light for you.
I can't go with you standing there.
Don't go far.
Hello?
Someone there?
Samantha!
Where are you?
Samantha?
She's never had two so close together.
There's been a lot going on.
Yeah, there sure has.
How could you not tell me, Will?
You didn't want to know.
We didn't want to know.
We made the decision
that we wanted to give her a clean slate.
No, you wanted to give her a clean slate.
I thought it would help
if she'd face things head on.
She's facing things head on now.
Is that why we're out here?
So you can expose her?
This is my life's work.
I spent years proving that
exposure therapy helped.
I don't want to hear it.
Just...leave.
I can't even bear to
look at you right now, Will.
Mom?
What is it?
Is that.
Did you do this on purpose?
What?
Did you bring her back here?
I didn't make a single turn all night.
I have no idea how we got here.
At least we still know where we are.
The campsite is just up the road.
Yeah, and the highway?
Will?
What?
Come on.
What is going on?
Won't start.
What do you mean it won't start?
I don't know.
Just give me a second.
You do some late night writing?
You fell asleep with the light on.
You killed the battery, genius.
We should be there by now.
It's right up ahead.
You said that 30 minutes ago.
We're going back.
All this walking is not good for her.
[Will] Evelyn!
[Evelyn] Come on, Sam, let's go.
I don't want you out here
alone with him around.
What are you going to do if he shows up?
Sit him down and ask
him about his childhood?
Jesus Christ will.
I knew your work was more
important to you than family, but this!?
Talk about a projection. That is not true.
What are we doing out here!?
I already said I was sorry.
Yeah. You're always sorry.
Sorry about never being
home for dinner because
of sessions running late.
Sorry about phone calls
in the middle of the night.
No wonder this happened to her.
Look at the kind of man
she has to look up to.
Always someone more important than her.
What are you talking about?
There is no one more
important to me than her.
And what about you, Evelyn?
You spent half of your life
in front of a damn make-up mirror.
Then slathering that crap all over her.
What kind of role model are you?
Teaching her that she
doesn't have any worth
unless she's all dolled up
like a damn prom queen?
I do not try to make her look
like a prom queen!
Evelyn, we're in the middle of nowhere,
and you look like you're ready
to walk on a frickin catwalk.
You don't think that plays on her psyche?
Just shut up!
You're talking about
me like I'm not even here.
You're both fuck-ups.
Okay?
So you can stop arguing about it.
Go with her. I'll find the site.
Samantha!
[Sam] I do not want to talk to you.
Fair. Then I'll talk.
You're right.
I am a fuck up as a mother.
I want to give you everything.
I never want you to feel unimportant,
unloved or unseen.
I guess I just never considered that
maybe your
everything is different from mine.
I got pregnant when I was 18.
Some strange guy I met at a party.
I don't even think
I ever knew what he looked like.
That's how drunk I was.
I didn't dare tell anybody.
My dad would have disowned me.
Maybe he would have killed
me first, then disowned me.
I took care of it by myself.
It was...
I don't regret it, though.
I wanted to make money.
Lots of money.
Be my own boss.
So I worked obsessively for years,
and it paid off.
And I always felt like I
was missing something.
When I met your father, I realized
that what I was missing was a family.
We tried having kids, but
it didn't work.
When our doctor suggested adoption.
I thought I couldn't love
anyone who didn't come from me.
But the first time I laid eyes on you
I fell in love with you.
In a way I have never loved anyone
in my whole life.
I've made mistakes.
Lots of mistakes.
Your father and I are not perfect.
But we are proud of you.
And we love you so much.
Please don't ever forget that.
You OK?
Yeah.
I just need a minute.
Okay.
Alone?
If that's okay.
I'll be by the car.
Yes!
Hello?
Can you hear me?
[John] Oh, it's a little
side business of mine.
Hey-
You scared me!
Got through to AAA.
Thank God
for Sam.
Isn't she in the camper?
No.
How could you leave her alone?
She was .. she was right there. I-
She wasn't out of my sight for
more than one minute.
Sam!
It's fresh mint.
Runs rampant in this area.
I hope you don't mind, but,
I gotta get this meat
right while it's fresh.
I'm surprised you found me out here.
I don't get many visitors.
I thought you were moving.
You live here long?
18 years.
My wife and I came out here
right after we got married.
It was an old hunting lodge at the time.
We get it for a good price.
We tried our best to fix it up.
Is that her?
Tried to do her justice, but
some beauty can't be captured.
Where is she?
Arlene passed away.
How?
She killed herself.
She'd always battled with depression.
I never thought she'd go through with it.
Our daughter
had been home with us a few weeks.
Things seem good.
She slept well.
She ate well.
She was perfect.
And one night.
I woke up and Arlene
wasn't in bed next to me.
I went to our daughter's crib.
She was gone, too.
I spent the whole night
searching for the two of them.
I called the police.
The next morning, the phone rang.
They said they found the baby
tangled up in a piece of driftwood
off the side of the creek.
Arlene's body had floated downstream.
I went to the hospital
to pick up my daughter,
but they wouldn't give it to me.
Said they were bruises on Arlene like
someone had pulled a in.
The papers ran with it.
And just like that, I lost everything.
I was charged with first degree murder.
Even though there was no evidence.
Couldn't afford a real lawyer. So -
some local one was given to me.
Convinced me to plead down
to voluntary manslaughter.
15 years.
Versus life.
I'm sorry
I haven't talked about this in a while.
You okay?
Can I use the bathroom?
Yeah.
I only got an outhouse, so I never
got around to putting in plumbing.
It's around the corner to the left.
Don't be scared.
I just needed to know you were all right.
That you were living with good people.
When they put me away
they didn't tell me anything about you.
Where you were, who you were living with.
Do you know what that does to a man?
Not knowing that his child is safe?
Stay away from me.
It was fate that we found each other.
Stay away.
We can be together.
Me? You. The baby.
We're family.
Blood runs deeper than anything.
They will never
understand you the way I do.
Come home.
Come home to your daddy.
Samantha!
Samantha!!!
[voices heard laughing]
[laughing continues]
She's not down there.
Where is she?
Oh! Sam!!
Oh my God, you okay?
Okay, sweetie.
Why don't you go?
Sweetie?
It's John.
There's pictures.
It's okay, it's okay.
It's okay my love. It's OK.
[Sam crying]
[Sam whimpering in pain]
It's okay.
[Sam whimpering]
Ow!
Ah, ouch!!
Ugh...
Where is she?
Asleep.
[Will] Oh.
Did you find him?
He wasn't there.
Oh, God!
Hey, look.
Look at me.
I'm not gonna let anyone hurt our family.
Okay?
I promise.
Hey! What?
What?
Well, you know, it's...
Just.
Oh, we thought there was.
[many voices talking]
Watch it tonight.
Hey baby?
You know you want me
Tell your kids!
Tell your children! Tell your children!
No. No! NO!!!!!
[chanting continues, "Tell your children!"]
Where are they?
It's a small town.
They said it might be a while.
I should've never brought us here.
I just,
I wanted to fix it.
So I could fix us.
You can't fix anyone, Will.
You know that.
Right?
Look,
I get why you
went searching into Sam's past.
I didn't want to know anything
about any of that.
I never did.
I don't want her past to define her.
I want her to have a clean slate.
But now that I know.
I'm glad that I know.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry too.
We should go in.
Is that Samantha?
I'm fine.
Go get her.
Sam? Sam?
Samantha?
Samantha.
[John] Samantha!
I'm so sorry.
[Evelyn] Will!!!! Get away from her!
Please don't do this.
Don't touch her!
Samantha. I'm coming baby. I got you.
[gunshot]
[John]
I just wanted to be with my baby girl.
I'm here baby.
Stay right where you are.
Nooooooo!
[thud]
Oh sweetheart!
Oh my God!
Honey!
Sam! Sam!
[door closes]
An then you gotta
OK
Just like that
I want to talk to John.
Goodnight, baby.
Goodnight, kiddo.
Some.
[ominous music grows]
[baby crying]
[baby crying continues]
Sam?
Can I have the baby?
Will!
Sam?
Samantha!!
[Sam sings a lullaby]
[Sam, singing] Guardian angels.
God will send. Me all through the night,
[a ghostly voice continues the singing]
[splash of water]
Perhaps most talked about ghosts
in Clinton County are the ones found here
at the crossing of Mill Creek.
What many locals know as Crybaby Bridge.
Excuse me.
I'm interviewing people
about the Crybaby Bridge incident.
And would you mind commenting?
We visited the bridge
when I was a teenager.
We actually yelled, I killed your baby.
And did you ever see anything?
No. We were too scared to stick around.
It's a nice walk in the fall.
The color of the leaves and all that.
Only thing I gotta say.
You bring snacks, drinks or whatever.
You take your trash with you.
There's so many places
that become local law and legend
that they're targets for vandals.
It's just so sad.
People have no more respect for nature.
I used to take girls out there
on Halloween
after I'd cruise around town in my cherry
red Chevelle.
Head out there for a little bit of chills
and thrills.
Fear is the greatest aphrodisiac.
Let me tell you.
They call it the cry baby
because, well, after nine months.
That's what you end up with.
Doctor glass, you've written
books on the Crybaby Bridge legend.
Would you mind commenting
on the latest tragedy?
Unfortunately, it's just
all too common a story.
A new mother killing herself and her baby.
It's a tragedy.
Yes, but it.
It has nothing to do with legend.
Oh, so you don't believe a ghost
had anything to do with it?
Certainly not.
The Clinton County Crybaby Bridge is
Well, it's an internet hoax
that was seated in the late 1990s.
If you do your research.
Crybaby bridges were popping up
all over the country at that time.
It was
Well, it was almost an overnight
appearance, you see.
Postpartum depression and psychosis was
not something that was
talked about until recently.
And to take such a tragic tale
and turn it into a kind of
amusement park, I just think it is.
It is personally, it is reprehensible
for a community to embrace.
You won't find me near that bridge.
Not with my babies.
Why is that?
Hey! I said keep it down in there.
Sorry.
So me and my friend Jesse,
we were driving.
We come up to this bridge
and we seen this white figure saying.
Where's my baby? Have you seen my baby?
We were terrified.
We had never seen anything like that
before.
All of a sudden, I heard this baby crying
in the waters of the river down below.
Don't get me wrong.
I feel sorry for this ghostly mom
or whatever searching for her baby.
And maybe she needed our help that day,
but we were just too scared.
You know?
Do you go there often? Sometimes.
And what do you do there?
You know, hang out and stuff.
Do you ever see or hear anything strange?
But like that lady and her baby?
No, it's just a story.